[Music]
Heat.
Hello. Good evening, good day everybody
and welcome to the 262nd episode of the
Ask Abaja show. I hope everybody is
doing fantastic.
Uh before we begin let us see who all is
there on the live chat. I can see Vun
Warrior, Daran Patil, Manisha Kardo, GK,
Vinyas, Xenomorphosis, Hunter, Kenway,
Shubhham S, Hitanu, Shri, Javahar, Lal,
Nehu G, Nai, G, Duv, Durya, Niha Sharma,
UCSS,
Samati, Adwit, Mata, Dirj, Kamat, Jimmy,
Chacha, Aijit, Chava. Well, what is
that? Pratam Sharma freedom from outcome
from Canada. Sam again uh nationalist
mystic SK geopolitical dubet from Indor
uh anonymous scientist whose questions I
have answered it looks like Dr. Patnik,
Games, Rich, Devil, Omar, ICMBBS, Rahul,
Dun. Um, uh, who else do we have? We
have plenty of people. Scanda, Janadan,
Janard, Yashwan, Sudir, Shiva, Dan S,
Rohitki, a Singh, Katalin, Yash,
Ds, Aradhya, Sharma, Nanch, Harshett,
Anul,
Chaki, Rala, Ravi Kumar, Pratam Sharma,
Sedhart, Adiga, Maklavin from Superbad I
suppose, Briesh SK, Shashank Koshik,
Polar Bear is here, Parto Shre A is
there artistic self Rishikes Gupta and
so many other people. I will not be able
to greet you all individually but thank
you so much for being on the live chat
and let us get going with some
questions. Shitra from Moscow
Tares.
Yes, it's good to see you sir. Okay,
let's get get going with some questions.
Uh ICMBB says what's your opinion on
NZ's Uber Mench idea? I think it's an
antithesis to Abrahamic moral values and
much more aligned with Dharmic ideology.
Well, I haven't read it in detail but
the Uber uber mench idea is this the
idea I believe
what's the idea
is it an emphasis antithesis to
Abrahamic moral values and is it aligned
to the dharmic ideology? I'll have to
refresh my memory about Niche's Uber
Bench idea. So, let's do a Google Let's
do a very quick Google search. Okay. And
then I'll that should be enough.
Okay. Let's quickly
uh Oberan obviously Superman but it's a
philosophical ideal represent the person
who has overcome traditional values and
societal constraints to create their own
meaning and values. It's not literal
superhuman overcoming nealism, creating
new values beyond good and evil etc. Not
a fixed state, not a social class, etc.
It's a philosophical ideal representing
a people, a person who has overcome
traditional values and so on and so
forth. Okay, that's the uber.
So, is this an anti antithesis to
Abrahamic moral values?
Um, what are Abrahamic moral values?
Uh, Abrahamic moral values are that you
confirm
You don't ask questions. You don't
think. You accept whatever is taught to
you by by your elders and whatever is
written in the book and you don't raise
questions and so on. And the Ubench is
kind of different from that, isn't it?
It's about u a person who overcomes
traditional values and societal
constraints to create your own meaning
and values. Well, that's totally
iconoclastic. Clearly it's totally
iconoclastic. It's definitely the way I
see it an antithesis to Abrahamic
uh values and norms. Is it aligned with
dharmic the dharmic ideology? Well, in
dharmic ideology you do question
everything and you are completely free
to to uh have your own values and and
live life your own way as long as you
don't harm anybody.
So yeah, it is more aligned with Dharmic
ideology as compared to the Abrahamic
moral values and it is definitely you
could say an antithesis to Abrahamic
moral values. Yeah, it is. Omar says
SM geopolitics and astrology experts
predict India will take back P in one or
two years but now as Trump is on
Pakistan's side, will this be possible
if we are at war again? Okay, look um I
have not made any such prediction. Of
course, I'm not an astrologer. I don't
know anything about astrology. So, I
will not comment about that. But I have
not pred predicted I I could perhaps be
seen as somebody who understands
geopolitics. Perhaps perhaps little bit
tora to
so I have not made a prediction that
India will take back P in one one or two
years. Uh Trump is very much favoring
Pakistan. You are absolutely correct in
your observation. Trump is very much
favoring Pakistan. Uh so will it be
possible if we are at war again?
Well first of all the question is will
we be at war again? Uh we had a
three-day war 3 and a half 4 day
whatever 3-day war and it was paused
because of external interference which
is Trump's interference.
Uh now Pakistan will regroup. It will uh
possibly learn the lessons of the
operation zindur and possibly bolster
its defenses and other capabilities and
so on uh and so on. So the question is
will we be at war again soon? Well, it
depends. It entirely depends on Pakistan
and Pakistan's uh behavior. If Pakistan
launches another terrorist attack on
India, we we will be at war again and
this time we may strike harder. So the
question is really
is Pakistan
possibly going to launch another terror
attack in the next one or two years? If
it does, we will be at war. Then the
question is if we are at war will we be
able to take back P? I'm not sure about
that. See the objective as of now is to
significantly degrade Pakistan's
military and terrorist capabilities.
Right? The military and terrorist
capabilities go hand in hand because
they are the same entity.
So if we can do that
and of course the nuclear blackmail has
been burst now. The nuclear weapons are
American weapons and the Pakistanis
won't be allowed to use them. I don't
think they will and if they do it's the
end of Pakistan. So I think that it's
unlikely for us to take back P in one or
two years. I don't know. I have no idea
about astrology. So I'll not comment
about that. But I have never said that
it's likely that it'll happen in the
next couple of years. It may definitely
happen in the next 10 to 20 years maybe
even 5 years but 2 years it's a I think
it's a short time frame.
The devil says what ideology did people
follow in ancient India and also compare
it with ideologies like communism etc.
One more question I have about dating in
ancient India. What's the question?
Ideology. India has never been an
ideological
uh civilization.
What did we follow in ancient India? We
followed dharma. The various schools of
thought of dharma. Dharma. Dharma right?
Whether it is uh whether it is Charvak
philosophy or Sananka philosophy or
Bimmana philosophy or Vidanta philosophy
or or Naya philosophy or whatever else
or Jina philosophy or Bodha philosophy
etc. These are all dharmic philosophies
and these are all different schools of
thought. Some are pretty different from
each other. Some are pretty and there's
still a lot of commonality. So that's
what Indians followed in ancient India.
We didn't have communism and whatever
else. We had nothing no such thing. So
these are not ideologies. These are
philosophical schools of thought. Each
philosophical school of thought had a
set of tenants which essentially were
models of the universe essentially.
Right? What were the what was the
universe like and what are the laws that
governed the universe and that and that
sort of thing. So that's what our
ancestors followed. There was no
ideology
as such.
Um yeah dating in ancient India I have
no idea.
We have lost our text so I have no idea.
Dating
games. Rich says, "Is it just too much
information flow or is the world
actually getting more unstable?"
Uh, also do you say thanks to Chat GPD
at the end of the conversation?
Well, if you're having conversations
with Chat GPD, maybe you should thank
Chat GPD for taking the time to have a
conversation with you. I I don't know.
It depends on the nature of the
conversation you're having with Chad
GPT. I have seen u photos of people
standing in subways with their phone and
this chat GPD on there and they are
talking to chat GPD like it's a
girlfriend of theirs you know that sort
of conversation. So it depends on what
sort of conversations people have with
chat GPD right I mean ch seems to be a
pretty powerful tool but people are
using it for all these silly purposes
like creating memes. I mean it's fine to
create memes and all but yeah most
people will use technology for these
little little things. Um
now is it too much information flow? Is
the world getting more unstable? Both
both things are both of both of things
are happening. There is more and more
information out there in on the
internet. No question about that. And
most of it is now becoming noise. It's
just noise and very little actual signal
high value signal high quality signal.
So there's a tremendous amount of
information. And most of it is just
generic noise. People just mumbling and
blabbering. Um so there is that. But is
the world also getting more unstable? It
is getting more unstable geopolitically.
So it's a combination of all these
factors. My dear friend,
Dr. Ritik Patna says 29 million
subscribers. YouTuber said that J.
Shankar is a failed diplomat. We have no
allies. Not even even Nepal, Bhutan, Sri
Lanka support China. Can you give real
clarity? I don't know who this okay
whatever YouTuber is we have no allies
that is correct of course we have no
allies we don't have any formal alliance
uh agreement with any nation
we don't have something like what NATO
has which is a formal uh agreement
uh so we have no allies no official
allies we we have partners we are
multi-aligned we have lots of alignments
with various nations in based on various
uh shared interests but we have no
allies Okay.
Does Bhutan support China? I disagree.
Bhutan doesn't support China. Does Sri
Lanka support China? Not quite. During
the Raja Paka era, Sri Lanka was under
the Chinese uh sphere of influence.
Today, it is more
more aligned towards the US and to some
extent India, not that much China. So, I
would disagree with that. I disagree
about Sri Lanka. I disagree about uh
Bhutan. When it comes to Nepal, the
politicians are all left aligned, which
means that they many of the politicians
are aligned with China. That's no
question. There's no question about
that. But culturally, Nepal is Indian.
We are the same people as the Nepalese.
They are the same as us culturally,
genetically, etc. Uh, and there is a
significant uh push, there's a
significant desire one sees from time to
time in the Nepalese population to see a
restoration of the monarchy. If that
happens, then Nepal will not be
pro-china. But right now, Nepal is kind
of pro-China. kind of to some extent
right so I think that answers that so
I've answered the question about the
allies about Nepal about Bhutan about
Sri Lanka is Jashanka a failed diplomat
I mean why is he a failed diplomat what
has he done to deserve the tag of being
a failed diplomat I don't understand
that he's a reasonably good pretty good
diplomat
uh he's taking care of our interests how
has he failed I I fail to understand
that so I don't care if this person has
29 million YouTube uh subscribers or
whatever. Uh I I strongly disagree with
that with that nonsensical
uh claim whatever it whoever the person
is.
Okay. Rabi says top peerreed Indian
geneticist
Nariman.
Are you talking about Vagish?
You're talking about Vagish Nariman. One
second. Is it Vagish?
Vages.
Ah you're talking about Vageshariman top
peerreed Indian geneticist who works
with the David Reich lab he has
confirmed by confirmia
confirmed that R1A is not Indian it's
not native to India it came from Mars
it came from Venus it came via
immigration oldest R1A samples are this
many years old found in Russia blah blah
etc etc etc not India clearly clearly
indicating external origin
Oh my god, this is the end of the world
for us.
This is a work in progress. Okay, and he
may be a top peer-reviewed guy, but
okay, now he has his own lab apparently
and so on. This is a work in progress.
Look, please understand one thing, my
friends. Let me explain this very
clearly.
This is obviously all related to the
Arian invasion/migration/ourism/
picnic theory, right? The migration
theory became a the invasion theory
became a migration theory. Now it's
going to be a tourism theory and
eventually picnic theory. But understand
this my friends
this claim
of this aran invasion migration whatever
it's not going to be settled through
genetics.
Why do I say this? Please understand.
Why do I make make this statement? It
will not be settled through genetic
data.
Hm. Because the Arian invasion/migration
theory has two two central claims.
First claim is that Hinduism
is foreign to India.
Second claim Sanskrit is foreign to
India.
Now from your DNA can you can you
determine what was the religion of the
person and what was the the language of
the person? You can't. So what's this
pointless nonsense about R1A and
genetics and all
and the R1A question is still an open
question. There is research happening in
India. Okay, let the Indian research
come out. There is research happening at
the Birbalani lab
with with a significant set of Indian
samples. Let the research come out.
We'll see about that. So first so first
of all the genetic question is a totally
separate question. But the real central
claims of the RN and vision theory are
the question about religion and
language. Hinduism and SKR and they want
to claim they're claiming that Hinduism
and Sanskrit are foreign to India. These
are the central claims. It has nothing
to do with genetics.
And let them prove this. Are they are
any of them in a position to prove that
Hinduism is foreign to India? It
originated outside India and Sanskrit
originated author of India. Let me let
me I I will wait for that to be proven.
It will never be proven. And that's
that's the whole deal.
Anonymous scientist says the UK Navy is
a stealth lol F-35B fighter jester in
India. What are my thoughts? I am
beginning to think it's a it's a Trojan
horse.
I mean they said that the thing ran out
of was running out of fuel. That's why
it had to make an emergency landing in
India. Fine. But why is it here for 5
days? Take it back.
take your flying trash can back. Why
haven't you taken it back this far? I am
beginning to think it's think that it's
a Trojan horse. It's it's a spying
operation of some kind. I don't know. I
don't know what the deal is. I have no
idea why it's still there. If they are
not willing to take it back, we should
impound it. You know the Indian
government and custo customs officials,
they love to impound things. They put
their stamp and their seal and all that.
Take it, Leelo.
Impound it.
Uh Shivam says let's be honest India
will never c catch up to China. Well
then Shivam Bakshi please go to China.
Why are you here?
Why are you so pessimistic?
I see lots of Indians like this. I don't
understand why. Let's be honest. You be
honest. It's it's for it's it's your
perspective. It's your worldview that
India will never catch up with China. I
strongly disagree.
I have the utmost utmost faith
in the in Indian civilization
you know
most people are average right we know
that right that's why the world a the
word average exists most people are
average another word for average is
mediocre so the world is average the
world is mediocre so the same applies to
India but India has more exceptional
people than anywhere else in the world
the system is horrible no question about
it but we going to prevail
So I just don't agree with this
defeatist mindset that you have sir that
India will never catch up with China. Oh
we are doomed. We will never be good
etc. That's not for me. Please don't
please don't
it's that that mindset is not for this
this channel. Please don't bring it here
sir. Okay let's be positive. Let's be
optimistic. What's the point of this? I
don't get it. Anonymous scientists
earth. Well thank you sir. Thank you
very much. Very kind of you. Gapati
says,
"Hey Abijit, previously you mentioned
there were only six sovereign states."
Well, I used to say four. Now it's five,
but you saying six. Somebody will now
say seven. Seven colors of the rainbow.
So, Iran wasn't in that list. Their
actions don't seem subservient. It
serves their national interest. Who is
their master?
I have historically said there are four
sovereign states. Of late I have uh
revised that estimation and now and and
I now say there are five sovereign
states. I have never said there are six
but maybe you must have uh you must have
heard something and okay so that's
that's fine. So which are the which are
the sovereign states? The US, Russia,
China, India and Israel.
So according to me there are five
sovereign states not six. Okay. Now you
are asking about Iran and it's a good
question. Why do I say that Iran is not
fully sovereign, right?
Because they are critically dependent on
two nations, Russia and China.
Critically dependent. And if these
nations essentially don't come and stand
with Iran, then Iran could end up losing
its independence. Forget about
sovereignty. It's it'll end up losing
its territorial integrity.
uh and Iran is deeply dependent on on
these two nations and you know it's cut
off from the rest of the world because
of American sanctions which has caused
the situation and put Iran in a
situation where it is without these
donations it essentially can't survive
without Russia and China. So it means
that it's critically depend on them
which means it is not fully sovereign
right their actions
look their actions they are obviously in
defiance of the US because they have no
other choice
but without the support of Russia and
China Iran is doomed please understand
that
um Adwat Ma is asking two questions how
was Hitler's economy it was great Hitler
actually transformed the German economy
okay it's a very interesting chapter of
history. He did transform the German
economy. He brought Germany up from its
knees. How was France after Napoleon?
Not so good. Not so good. The Napoleonic
wars kind of ruined France and it it
caused a lot of changes across the world
in Europe and also in South America and
where not. You know, very interesting.
So, lots of um lots of you know second
order, third order effects and so on.
Rahul, well, thank you so much sir. very
kind of you. Um, Vic Post says, "Why are
90% English-speaking whites racist to
Indians?"
Well, I'm not sure everyone's racist.
I'm not sure about the 90% figure, but
you do have racism against Indians. Why
is there racism against India? Because
India is daring to rise again. You see,
India is a nation of brown people who
apparently are inferior to white people
according to the white supremacist
mindset. I'm not I'm sure not all whites
think that way. Okay, there are nice
people as well in the world. Please
please understand there are many nice
people in the world. There are many
non-racist people in the world. But
historically the west has been super
racist and they have
at some point in time in history they
began to imagine that white skin makes
them superior and we are a nation of
brown people. Look at this brown skin.
So some of them believe that you know
the fact that they have white skin makes
them superior and also
we are a nation of brown people who were
subjugated by the whites for two and a
half centuries. We were completely
destroyed. Our economy was devastated.
Everything of value was sucked out of
India. And look at us today. We are
rising up on our feet again. We are the
fourth largest economy. We have we have
the tearity to have nuclear weapons.
We have the temerity to not participate
in American sanctions against Russia,
another eastern nation.
So we we we were supposed to be coolies
but we are standing up and we are saying
we are independent. How dare we? How
dare we? So that's why there is this
upsurge of racism against us. It's a
good thing. It tells us if these if
these racists are all upset. Once again,
I'm saying not all white people are
racist. Okay, there are many nice people
as well. But if those racist white
people are upset, we must be doing
something good. So why are we upset
about it? We should be celebrating. Yay.
Yay. Yay. It's going well. We're doing
really well.
Amand
Anandra himate says battle of Ajankur a
100 years war between France and UK. The
battle of Ajankur was a supreme victory
I think with battle of who was it Henry
VII was it the English archers who were
plucking the U
the the English long bow made of U wood
and they would pluck the U wood and
unleash the arrows. When was the battle
of Ajanur? I don't remember. Let let's
let's quickly do a quick Google search.
I think I'm still oldfashioned. I don't
do chat GPT searches. I still do Google
searches. Right.
Okay. Battle of Ajaku. Yes. So, who were
the 100 years was who were the belly
belligerents?
Henry V, not Henry VII. Oh, I see.
So, they defeated the French. Now, as
you can as you can see, you have English
archers with the English long bow. There
you have it, the long bow. So, yes, I do
have I do remember some of this. Yes.
Yes. And yeah, it was a significant
victory by the English over the accursed
French. Yes. They the two nations were
were they they were enemies for a
thousand years. They hated each other.
The the French called the English leos
beef and the English called the French
the frogs. lifrogs. I I don't know why
but whatever. Um yeah, so it was this
period of a 100 years of of of hostility
between the two nations indeed.
Yes. And then that that hostility lasted
a long long time and I don't think it's
entirely gone away even now. Yeah. Okay.
John says, "I'm 27 years old. I want to
study BSc physics. Do you think it's too
late? In India, normally taking a
bachelor's this late is looked down
upon." Well, it how do you care what
people think? If you want to do it, you
do it. As long as it's it provides some
value to you and and and and you know
enhances your life in some way. It's up
to you. I mean there are people who do
their PhD at 70 years of age because
they wanted to have a PhD. I had this
dream of having a PhD. So now that I'm
70, I'll do a PhD. There's no such thing
as right or wrong. If it's something you
want to do, then tell yourself that the
world can go take a hike. I'll do what I
like. I don't think it's too late. I
don't think so. Okay. But as long as it
it it's it's useful to you or it's
something that you really want to do, it
should not come in the way of your
career or whatever. As long as it
doesn't hurt you or harm you in some
way, who the hell cares what the world
thinks? Do what you like. Yeah. Go for
it. All the best. Go for it.
UC says, "What are some more delusions
Indians believe in?" Oh, I had made a
video. What about delusions? Didn't I
delusions? What delusions do Indians
believe in? I have to think about it
because I think I listed all the major
delusions off the top of my head over
the video and yeah, Vishwaguru and
superpower and all that stuff. What
other delusions? Um, I I love to think
about it. I I I if I tell you now, I
think I'll repeat all the points that I
I had raised the other day.
But yeah maybe I can think about it
properly and make a list written down
list and maybe maybe then I can answer
the question. So at this point in time
yeah I don't know more delusions wish
for sure superpower for sure uh India
India system is the best come on are you
kidding me India's education system is
garbage and um I suppose there could be
many more delusions. So yeah
um
Rohan says will will Armenia's defense
supply halt if Iran fails? If if Iran
falls if Iran falls, Armenia also falls.
Yeah, if Iran falls, Armenia also falls.
Turkey will go for the jugular. Turkey
won't do it directly. They will have
their minions araijan do it. So yeah,
Armenia's future kind of depends on
Israel on on on Iran not falling. And do
you see Israel is supporting Azarbaijan
against Armenia while India is
supporting Armenia against Azarbaijan.
Very strange uh uh situation. Zishan
says, "If you consider yourself an
Indian patriot, why speak English, the
language of my of our colonizers, not
only do you speak in English, but you
can barely speak Hindi?" I know I should
be ashamed of myself and I have said
this multiple times that this is a
strong indication of the fact that I'm
mentally colonized. Right? One of the
reasons I speak English is that I want
the world to understand our perspective.
That's one reason. The other reason is
that I am not very good at Hindi. I I I
I can speak Hindi but I'm not that
fluent. the the words and concepts and
and all of that doesn't come naturally
to me because I've never studied Hindi
properly because I spent a lot of my
formative years outside of the country.
Right?
So I I suppose it may be possible to be
an Indian patriot while being mentally
colonized to a certain extent.
But I will very much encourage everybody
uh to prioritize your mother tongue and
your national languages. And I think
that Sanskrit should we should revert to
Sanskrit and if we do then I promise you
I will stop speaking English and I'll
I'll go back to speaking Sanskrit only
and I'll learn it properly. But the
other reason is that I don't consider
Hindi to be the national language. Hindi
is not Hindi doesn't deserve the status
of a civilizational language for India
or even a national language. The only
language that is worthy of being a
national or civilizational language is
Sanskrit. Not Hindi. I am not a fan of
Hindi and another reason is that the
Hindi I have learned is the Hindi you
you essentially speak on the streets of
Mumbai. So I'm not sure how
civilized that Hindi is.
Uh so multiple reasons and Hindi the
other reason is that Hindi has so many
foreign loan words. I don't want to end
up speaking foreign loan loan words. So
because of all these reasons I prefer to
speak English.
Yeah, I know these are not these are all
excuses of course. So ideally I should
be speaking Sanskrit but then if I do
that nobody will understand me and so
on. So because of all these reasons I
speak English. But I take your point. I
know you're not trying to be
disrespectful. You're making a good
point here. And I have said this I am I
do suffer from mental colonization
because of the way I grew up and I was
raised. I was exposed to English. I
wasn't exposed to other languages and I
was exposed to other foreign languages
beyond English and so on. Yeah.
Spade says we are Rossia Sar.
Well,
we are Rossia Sar. Well, if you say so.
I'm not sure what you're saying, but
okay. Thank you.
Vamshi Khalm says Bahalik. Kingdom of
Bishma is separate from Gandhar. Well,
Bahalik and Gandhar are essentially
separate. Right. But if you look at if
you look at Gandhar from the perspective
of today's Afghanistan, then Bahalik
comes within that. But historical
Gandhar was not the entirety of today's
Afghanistan.
It had some of today's Kyber Pakuna. It
had the Chitral region and so on and
various parts of Afghanistan, but
Bahalik was separate. So you make a good
point. No question. But if you if you
want to superimpose the word Gandhar on
today's Afghanistan then bulk comes
within that doesn't it?
So yeah so yeah if you want to be very
very super precise and right then what
you are saying is indeed correct sir
geopolitical dub sir thank you so much
thank you so much
uh feminist khan slayer sharin
are documentaries good for world history
overview well I'll tell you what
documentaries are great you can learn a
lot from a documentary a good
documentary but not from a short
documentary documentary. Let's say you
want to understand the the Second World
War, for example, and you will watch a
60-minute documentary to understand the
Second World War. You won't get much
knowledge or context or information from
a 60inute documentary about the Second
World War. But there are some
documentary series that are like 20, 30,
40 episodes each 1 hour long. I I
suppose there are. If you watch that, if
you invest that much time in doing that,
then you may actually learn a lot about
world history without having to read
about it. So it depends even
documentaries you to watch them
seriously and in a short documentary
won't teach you much. Okay.
Adi Jin says namaste first of all if
Iran becomes a US vasal could this be
part of a US India collusion? India take
America takes Iran and India handles
Pakistan.
You think America will allow India to
handle Pakistan, take over Pakistan? It
will never happen.
Never going to happen. Would be nice if
it was the case. But it's not the case.
So if you watch the Indian interest
episode that I just did before this live
stream, if you watch that, you will
understand why it'll never happen. Trump
himself is personally deeply invested in
Pakistan. Why would he hand Pakistan
over to India? Why would he have India
handle Pakistan? He wants to personally
handle Pakistan and exploit the
resources, extract the resources, oil,
gas,
rare earths and also crypto and so on so
forth. Why would he hand over Pakistan
to India? Not going to happen. And Iran
becoming a US itself is a is a terrible
terrible thing to happen. So yeah.
Uh strike says your views on Israel
today genocidal or defendant? Look
honestly it's somewhere in between.
Of course, there's no question about the
fact that it has suffered terrorist
attacks. Tremendous terrific, horrible,
inhuman terrorist attacks. No question
about it. It's a nation that's
surrounded essentially by enemies.
Historically, it's been that way. I
mean, if you see the 48 war, the 67 war
and so on so forth. Yeah. It's been
surrounded by enemies. And as as such,
it's it's perhaps the Israeli psyche has
developed a siege mentality. If you look
at the Israeli population, it's not a
nation of civilians. Honestly speaking,
the moment you're 18, you have to
undergo uh compulsory military training
unless you have some some some issues.
So most people undergo three years of
military training.
They all know how to handle weapons and
grenades and whatnot. They all know how
to fight. It's not a nation of
civilians. So the whole nation because
of the surroundings has has evolved in
that manner.
Right? And they suffered this terrible
horrible attack from Gaza. the October
2023 terrorist attack when I don't know
hundreds maybe thousands of Israelis
were killed and then they launched this
retaliation on the on Hamas in Gaza and
the people of Gaza support Hamas so they
well it is what it is so I'm not sure
how many people have died in Gaza Gaza
has been turned into
I don't know rubble maybe 50,000 plus
people have died in Gaza so some would
say this is genocide others would say
that this is retaliation from Israel and
justifiable retaliation to look out for
its national interest. So I would say
look u this is not my fight. I
completely support Israel's right to
self-defense.
Okay. Um so it's complicated. I would
say it's definitely a defendant. But do
does its defense uh what what it did in
its defense does it constitute genocide?
Um
not sure.
But if you're
I think if you're defending yourself
against um a bunch of people who are
determined to end you, to destroy you,
to eradicate you from the river to the
sea, I don't think it's genocide. Yeah.
So, and and Israel has done its best to
give a two-state solution and all that,
you know, it tried its best. So,
overall, I would I I would I would see
Israel as a defendant in this matter.
Not in the Iran Israel thing, but in the
Israel Palestinian Israel Gaza thing.
Israel is a defendant. That's how I see
it.
Rahul says, "You look like Bumarinari."
I I am not a Persian. I'm not Pi. Come
on. How can you say that? I'm I'm I'm
deeply upset. It It hurts my feelings.
You calling me Persian? I'm not Persian.
Okay. Anyway, uh no, seriously, what
could be the what would be the
probability estimate that if the US is
drawn into Israel, Iran, China would use
the distraction to take Taiwan?
I think it is unlikely.
Even if the US is drawn into the Israeli
Iran conflict, the US has sufficient
forces
in the Indo-Pacific region in the in the
South China Sea region to prevent China
from taking Taiwan. Or if China does
take Taiwan, it'll inherit nothing.
It'll inherit ruins and ashes. So I
think it's still too early for China to
make a move on Taiwan. Even if the US is
drawn into Israel Iran because Iran is
an important asset for China. If Iran
falls and China well China loses it's
its it's one of its major sources of
cheap energy and so on. So it doesn't
make sense to for China to make a move
on Taiwan at that point in time. So I
think from the way I see it, others may
see it differently. The way I see it,
uh, if the US is drawn to the Iran
Israel thing, China most likely will not
use the distraction to take Taiwan. I I
doubt it.
Shivam Bakshi says, uh, my previous
comment about China was not pessimistic.
We were a great civilization. I agree.
We were a great civilization. I agree
with you. But practically, we need to
completely change. I once again agree
with you. In the current state, we
promote mediocrity, not excellence, like
China. Again, I agree with you. I agree
with you in all these points. We were a
great civilization. We no longer are.
That's a hard fact of life. We have to
accept. We need to change completely. We
need to reform the system completely top
to bottom. I agree with you. In the
current state, we promote mediocrity. We
seek out mediocrity and we promote it.
And we seek out excellence and destroy
it. I completely agree with you. So,
there are these tremendous problems that
we face. But I'm still optimistic. I I I
don't know. It's just hardwired into me
genetically. I I'm not capable of being
pessimistic. Um so I agree with you and
I and I take your points completely
completely 100% correct. I agree with
you. But I still think we'll beat them.
Uh Nathan Jen, well thank you very much
sir. Batman sir, thank you.
Uh Vic post says uh my family tree has
160 names of uh generations starting
from my grandfather in our village
temple in Uttar Pradesh Ishtv. How many
years of continuity would I have? How
can I preserve its documentation? Well,
that's fantastic. 160
the names of 160 generations. 160
generations of ancestors. Well, that's
that's that's quite a lot, right? So uh
the question you're asking is how many
years of continuity do do you have first
of all that's the first question. So we
can calculate this in two different
ways. The first calculation is that one
generation is represents 20 years. Okay.
So if one generation represents 20 years
it means 10 generations is 200 years. Uh
10 generations is 200 years.
So 16 generations
uh sorry 10 generations is 200 years
100 generations is 2,000 years
and 160
what's 160 32 3,200 years.
Yeah. So if we calculate one generation
as representing 20 years, you have 3,200
years of continuity.
But if one generation is instead of 20,
it's 25,
then let's calculate, right? So if if
one generation is 25 instead of 20, then
160 * 25 is 4,000 years. So you have
between 3,200 to 4,000 years of
continuity that you're aware of. And
that's that's amazing. It's fantastic,
right? That needs to be treasured and
and preserved.
So now the question is how can you
preserve this documentation?
Well, it must be written down somewhere.
What you can do is take pictures and and
upload to the cloud or wherever and
maybe print it out and keep multiple
copies. That's one way of preserving it
documentation. Secondly, you make your
relatives aware of it and you give give
each of your relatives a copy. So that
way at least some of the copies survive
over the years that sort of thing. Um so
yeah and yeah so that's that's one of
the things you can do make multiple
copies of the documentation digital
copies physical copies Xerox copies
printouts whatever and distribute among
all your relatives and explain to them
how how incredibly valuable this is
between 3,200 to 4,000 years of history
you have recorded. That's amazing.
Awesome.
Spade says if you take away US support,
Israel won't survive. It will be hard to
see Israel survive if the US support
disappears. So yeah. Um I love India
says today a big YouTuber German model
tried to brainwash how India failed in
geopolitics and Manm Singh and Obama had
good relations and J Shankar and Modi
destroyed our foreign relations
completely.
Somebody said that there's a YouTuber
with 29 million followers. Now, someone
is saying that a YouTuber is German
model other the same person.
When you put these two together, I seem
to be getting a sense of who the person
could be. And if that is the person I'm
thinking about, then I'm not surprised
at all. Then I'm not surprised at all.
So, what can I say? People have agendas.
People have agendas. People have masters
that they have to serve. And that's why
they do these things. You see when you
have masters to serve political masters
or who have or geopolitical masters then
you will say these things. How have
Jungar and Modi destroyed our foreign
relations? You think Manuhan Singh was
was a leader to look up to? You think
Obama was a leader to look up to by the
way and so on. So listen I have nothing
to say about this. I I have no interest
in commenting about such people people
who make such claims is below my dignity
I would say. Uh, Rahul says, Rahul Vijak
says, "Big fan, regular watcher, please
keep it keep it going." Well, thank you
so much. I really appreciate that. Thank
you so much for watching. Thank you and
for your support.
Uh, Dhiraj says, "I I sir, I love you."
Well, thank you so much. I love you
back. Thank you so much.
Summer Tachara says, "Religion is is it
still a factor between the West and the
Middle East?" Religion has never been a
factor. Religion has been a tool that
the west has used to divide and conquer
and and rule the Middle East. And when
it comes to religion, look from from
outside for us, Islam is just one
religion, but from inside, Islam has so
many different sects and schisms and
whatnot.
Um, and very different multiple flavors
you could say of I don't know the right
way to use to say it or whatever. So
religion has been used to control the
region but the real factor in the Middle
East has historically been oil and
fossil fuels not religion.
Um Akil JK says did Shinszu AB support
Christian missionaries? I am not aware
of that. I'm not aware. Did he? Well, he
was a he was one of the rare Japanese
nationalists, a good man.
And I did not see him as being
pro-Christian the way I saw him, but I
don't know. I'm not aware of it as as
far as I know.
VS says, "Did Nazi Germany have a
military-industrial complex?" Um, what
were the conglomerates or banks that
were involved?
They did have a military-industrial
complex. I'm not sure about the banks.
Maybe the Deutscha Bundes Bank if it
still if it did exist at the time. I'm
not sure about the conglomerates. But I
can tell you what were the companies.
There was Hankl.
Uh Hankl it produced uh aircraft. There
was
there was fauulf there was Mercedes.
Um
and then there were various German uh
state-owned agencies, the ones that
developed cruise missiles and ballistic
missiles, the first ever cruise
missiles, the first ever ballistic
missiles and so on. And uh
Messith was one and so on. So yeah, they
had a tremendous military-industrial
complex, tremendous. They had some of
the brightest minds that ever existed.
They pioneered so many technologies. the
jet engine,
the cruise missile, the ballistic
missile and so much more the Germans. So
yeah, they were they were tremendous.
You have to admire what they did. You
don't have to admire their ideology and
other stuff but the scientific
excellence, the engineering excellence
was was incredible
and the Americans tapped into that and
so did the Russians and that's how the
American space program began. That's how
the Russian space program began and the
Chinese space program and everything
else and the jet engine programs and so
on.
Samir Chawan says, "After interacting
with the Chinese in Singapore, I feel
Chinese culture is very closer to us."
Well, I agree. I agree. The Chinese
prayer practices, etc., they're proud of
their culture. But if we call them
Chinese, they hate it. Do you think
think the same is the case with us
outside of India. So, first of all,
Chinese culture is very close to our
culture. If you meet Chinese people,
especially not younger people from
recent generations, but slightly older
people, they are very much like us. When
you meet a Chinese person, you don't
really feel
a cultural difference or a cultural
shock. When you meet a person from the
west, from Western Europe, etc., from
the US, they are culturally
significantly different from Indians. If
you're not used to it, you you will feel
a cultural shock. But the moment you sit
down with a Chinese person and talk, you
will feel there's no cultural difference
between us. The Chinese are very close
to us culturally and that's why India
and China should be friends but we are
not. It's it's really sad. We are
culturally very similar. We are overall
philosophically mentally etc. Uh from
the perspective of culture, tradition
etc. We are very similar India and China
practices. China has historically been
for the past 2,000 years a polytheistic
kind of culture and so on. And the
Chinese are proud of the culture. But
I'm not sure if we call them Chinese
hated. I'm not sure why that is.
Maybe in Singapore they don't want to be
called Chinese. I don't know what it is.
Um, is the same the case with us outside
of India? I'm not sure Indians will hate
it if you call them Indians outside of
India. I'm not sure that's the case.
Singapore may be a different case study,
but overall I don't think Indians who
who are second generation immigrants,
third generation immigrants, I'm not
sure if they hate it if they're called
Indians. I'm I'm not I've not seen that
personally. Uh, Takur says the oldest R1
skeleton PES 001 is from Russia. The top
three oldest R1A remains are from
Russia, Western Europe. Indian team
confirms Rak Rakar's autosomal DNA had
no R1A supporting mainstream. Are we
concluding something? Sir, like I said,
this is a work in progress. See in India
h in Batw in India, we have a hot humid
climate not considering northern India.
So the region where you have the
so-called indis valley culture harapan
culture civilization that that period of
forestry that is a pretty rainy place
hot humid place right western India
present day Gujarat Rajasthan Hana
Punjab and and Cinda and so on all of
those regions pretty heavy rainfall
pretty warm climate human remains don't
last in such climate so that's why you
will never find an Indian skeleton of an
Indian that is 12,000 50,000 years old
they will all disintegrate in that time.
So even if we have had R1A from 20,000
years ago, you won't find it because
that that that will have disintegrated
by now unless you go to places like like
Ladak etc where you have found signs of
human habitation going back 13 14,000
years but we haven't found skeletons
from that place because obviously people
would not want to live there. It's a
very very harsh climate and so on.
So I think it's too early to conclude
anything. What we need to do in we need
to have a 10,000 genome project in
India. Take at least 10,000 samples of
of present current current DNA
from all across India from all
population groups and do a deep study
and from that we will find out where the
origin of R1A was. How do we find out
the origin of Aron Arwa if we don't have
ancient samples? How do we determine
where Arbanet originated from if we
don't have ancient samples? How do we do
that? Well, there are ways of doing it.
It's a very clear rule in genetics.
What's the rule? The place where you
have the highest diversity within a
haplo group is the most likely to be the
origin of that haplo group. So, R1A is a
cate. It's a haplo group, right? But it
has many sub haplo groups. it has many
uh daughter haplo groups R1 A1 A R1 A1 B
R1 whatever etc so so forth right so it
is very I mean I've heard from reliable
sources because I know people I know
some people India has the highest
diversity within R1A
compared to anywhere in the world but
that needs to be published once it is
published we can make it official so all
of these stories are fine in and so on
so forth. But the main question about
the Arian invasion migration theory is
not about genetics at all. Like I keep
on saying it's not about genetics. The
the the claim the central claims are
that Hinduism is foreign to India and
Sanskrit is foreign to India and they
have no way of proving it. That's why
they're going into the genetics route
and other routes. But yeah, whatever.
Um, Zishan says, "How can Indians even
dream of becoming a superpower if they
can't agree on what language to speak or
what for what form of government they
should have?" And I agree and that's why
I keep on saying that India is nowhere
going close to being a superpower.
India is nowhere close to being a
superpower. India is not even a proper
regional power right now. Right? And you
are absolutely right. We are too divided
all of us. We are divided by a thousand
factors. They are divided by linguistic
factors, religious factors, regional
factors, uh so-called cast factors and
God knows what what other factors they
find to to fight among each other and
divide and divide further. That's what
Indians do. We Indians excel at arguing
with each other all day, all night.
We're the most argumentative people in
the world. We think our arguments will
change the world and so on. We can't
agree on anything.
So what India needs to change is a
superhuman leader. We've had superhuman
leaders in the past, taller than
anything we've experienced recently.
Only a leader with tremendous fortitude
can take the nation by the scruff of its
neck, force it to unite, impose one
thing on the nation which is beneficial
for the nation and take it forward. And
then India will not be a nation. It will
be a civilization. A civil a
civilizational proper civilizational
entity. That's what needs to happen. The
current shape and form of things is all
about mediocrity.
Have 50 different languages and fight
about languages. In your curriculum, you
have to learn three languages and the
form of government is the worst possible
form of form of government and so on so
forth. So you are right Zishan. In the
current shape and form, we cannot dream
of becoming a superpower. We have all
the potential but and the way things are
right now we are not going to be a
superpower but if things change somehow
or the other we who knows what could
happen.
Um Salvatore is brother. Ah Damon Damon
is here. Okay. So Damon says please
suggest a toz World War II campaign best
source.
Uh World War II campaign. You you mean
reading material or or or documentaries?
I can't remember when I was a kid like
like 7 8 years old 9 years old when I
was abroad I grew up in Europe for a
while I was fascinated with
documentaries about the second world war
black and white documentaries and all
but I don't remember what those
documentaries were called so I don't
remember when it comes to books uh
um Anthony Bivore
I think is a good is a good source I
yeah it's very hard for me to remember
the names of books because I've read so
And the war that ended peace is probably
about sec the first world war. Anthony
Bour wrote about the second world war
possibly if I'm not sure. The guns of
August is about the first world war. Uh
so I'll tell you how to find the best
sources. Go to your favorite online
portal website
where you can order books whether it's
Amazon or Flipkart or whatever the hell
else and search for Second World War.
Search for books and find the books that
have the highest ratings and more than
100 reviews at least 4.5 and then if it
has at least 100 reviews and a 4.5 plus
rating it's guaranteed to be a good a
good book. So you can do that all right
Damon
Sai Kumar says how can we relate Iran
Israel war to heartland theory. Okay map
have we opened the map today? Well we
shall see the map now.
Heartland theory, rimland theory. So
Mackander's theory of the world island
says that the world has a rimland and a
heartland. The heartland is the
heartland of Eurasia which is China,
Russia, Kazakhstan, Central Asia, all of
that Ukraine. And the and the door to
the heartland is in Ukraine for the
west. Ukraine is the gateway to the
heartland. And then there are the
rimland nations like India and Iran and
the Arab nations and all which according
to Mckendra will remain in the periphery
of the world. So if you want to control
the world island, you have to control
the heartland which is Russia and China
in the central Asia. And to control the
heartland, you need a gateway to the
heartland which is either Ukraine or one
of the rimland nations. So Iran could be
a rimland nation that could be one of
the gateways to the heartland. And and
Ukraine is another one. So if the west
wins Ukraine and Iran, then there you
have it. They are they are on their way
to to conquering the heartland and
ruling the world forever. So that's how
it relates to that's how Iran Israel war
relates to the heartland theory.
Sankit says Jenzi role in building our
nation in the upcoming years. Look in a
few years people like me will be will be
gone and people like Jenzi will be in
our place and so eventually you will
have a Jenzi prime minister or or or or
king of the country or queen of the
country. Right? So eventually Gen Z is
going to be in the driver's seat and
when Gen Z is done the next one whatever
it is what is it called beta
whichever generation it is beta they'll
be the next ones yeah everybody plays
their role we are links in a chain the
chain goes back thousands of years and
we are a continuation of that
okay okay I'm going to take another 10
15 minutes and then we'll be done okay
the question is what what this video our
history tells us that we A very
technologically advanced brahastraman's
nukes okay if you say so mentioned in
our vas where did all the tech go
without a single archaeological trace
was it taken from us by a super race
maybe we were so technologically
advanced that we we realized how
dangerous these frightening weapons are
and then we said that you know during
the kalyuga era nobody should have
access to these weapons because
otherwise they'll be used for very bad
purposes and that's why our ancestors
who are supremely super advanced. They
used their advanced technology to
eradicate all traces of this technology
and they hid it away. It maybe it'll be
revealed only when the cycle changes
again and satyugu returns. I mean that's
what I can say. I don't know possibly
possibly right without evidence you can
make such claims because we don't have
any evidence. So maybe that's that's the
case perhaps.
Nikil Shivasav says is there a risk of
India becoming a vasal of China? Uh the
risk is very low. I I don't see India
becoming a vasal of China. Uh how would
that happen? That would happen only if
there's only in in what are the
scenarios in which this happens. One is
China defeats India militarily which is
highly unlikely. It would incur
tremendous risks if it if it wants to
have a prolonged military confrontation
with India. So China if it is a sane
nation will not fight any kind of
military conflict with India because the
risks are too high for both nations.
Right? So that way it can't make India.
Secondly the other way it could make
India is if there's a government change
or regime change in India and a
pro-China kind of government comes to
power. Well do you see that happening
anytime soon? So I think overall if you
look at these scenarios the risk of
India becoming a vasal of China is is
pretty low close to zero as of now as of
now.
Kapay developer thank you sir says why
does glo why do global economic models
rely on endless growth and expansion
what a good question often with
government aided rule bending by
monopolies to quash competition. How did
this happen and what's the way forward?
That's a great question. the global
economic model, the capitalist model.
Now I am now criticizing capitalism.
Please don't take it to mean that I am
in love with communism. Communism is
even worse. Okay, first of all,
communism is far worse. Capitalism has
its merits. But one of the things about
capitalism is its endless quest for
quarter upon quarter profits. an
infinite cycle of quarter upon quarter
profits on a finite planet.
How do these profits happen? By
plundering the earth for resources. At
the end of the day, it's all that
whether it's semiconductors, whether
it's electronic vehicles, whether it is
AI, which needs power, which mean which
needs either fossil fuels or something
else. At the end of the day, whatever we
are doing to generate the profits, we
are plundering the earth for resources.
It's a finite planet, but we want
infinite quarter upon quarter profits.
We're going to end up destroying the
planet.
Endless growth. You can't have endless
growth. You're going to end up eating
the planet alive and then there will be
nothing to do, right? It's it's a
disaster. It's a disastrous model. It'll
end up destroying the planet. And when
the planet is done, we'll move on to the
moon into Mars and destroy that too.
It's it's not a good model, right? So
how did this happen is the question. How
did the world come up with this model?
Well, it's an Abrahamic model. I think
if you read some of the Abrahamic holy
texts, they will say that the world is a
resource for you humans to exploit,
right? God gave you the land to exploit.
God gave you fish to fish and fowl to
eat. And I don't know something like
that. I have not read. I actually read
it once long time ago.
I was once stuck in a hotel in a city in
Europe when I was about 8 years old. I
was stuck in a hotel. I was under
instructions not to watch TV because TV
is bad for children's brains. So I I was
a reader. So I ended up reading a book
in a hotel room. So that's the day I
read the book of the Abrahamic people,
one of the the western oriented book,
right? I finished the book in one day.
It was a pocket version. So I kind of
read it when I was about 8 years old.
I don't remember much. Anyhow, so
according to the Abrahamic culture, the
world is a resource for humans to enjoy.
No, which humans? The humans who believe
in the Abrahamic God, the chosen ones.
So that gives rise to these models of
endless growth and exploitation and
plundering of the earth's resources on a
finite planet. Big problem.
Okay. Bageshwar Amy says, "In one
episode, you said you could read the
Persian script. How did you learn it?
And you do you have any recent Persian
ancestry in living memory? Uh I'm sure I
must have said something to the effect
but I did not say I could read the
Persian script. I said I read I learned
to read the Arabic script. Read and
write the Arabic script. The question is
how did I learn it?
It was probably in the year 2001
or something probably in 2001. I was ill
for a while and I was uh bedridden
at home for a few days and I was really
bored.
So I had I had this big fat dictionary.
It's called the American Heritage
Dictionary. So I opened it and it had a
section on alphabets and there was the
section on the entire Arabic alphabet. I
said okay let me try and trace that. Out
of curiosity and boredom, I learned the
Arabic alphabet in one in in one
afternoon and then I started using it to
write my name and all that. I could
write it very crudely, but I could. And
the Persian script, the today's Persian
script is is is a is a derivative of the
Arabic script. They have some words,
some pronunciations in Persian that the
Arabs don't have. For example, the the
the
pronunciation isn't there in Arabic,
it's in Persian. So, they use the the
triple dots for that and so on. And they
have purr which the Arabs don't have
right parsi instead of the Arab far and
so on. So that's how I learned it. I
anybody can learn it learn it in in a
couple of hours if you if you have the
inclination to do that. So that's how I
learned the Arabic script which also is
the basis for the Persian script today's
Persian script. Uh do I have any recent
Persian ancestry ancestry in living
memory? Not that I know of. As far as I
know the lineages that I am aware of
that go back about 1500 1600 years I
don't see any Persian ancestry in that
but of course it's not one line of
lineage that we have we have hundreds of
lines of lineage so who knows so my
ancestry is from western India Gujarat
and Persia is essentially a neighboring
state if you cross synind and
Balojasthan you're in Persia Persia is
neighbor is is kind of a neighboring
neighboring region for us uh so it's
possible there could have been
interconnections genetic and other
interconnections are possible who knows
but not that I'm aware of
Lok sir thank you so much thank you
Ankita says how would you analyze the
Iran Israel war in terms of their own
national interest existential rights and
sovereignty
uh their national interests are very
divergent Persia sees itself as an
ancient civilization and today it's Iran
not Persia and it's the Islamic Republic
not the Persian uh civilization ational
entity but Iran sees itself as as
a continuation of an ancient imperial
system which they were right uh and
therefore they they have bigger
ambitions they have lost territory just
like we lost territory our people still
yearn for the lost territories right at
Akandarat well there used to be Akand
Persia also they have also lost many
territories and they would like to
reunite that so they have these
ambitions of of reviving the old empire
to some extent and maybe expanding
territory which frightens some other
nations and Iran would love to have
nuclear weapons and to be a great great
country again. They used to be in the
past they used to fight the Romans and
the Greeks and everybody never fought us
because we were their people but they
fought everybody to to the west and
today to the to the west we have Israel.
So Israel is this new nation well new
nation 1948 onwards and they have they
have always been under siege they have
siege mentality and they are the well
the best friend of the US the
unconditional ally of the US the US is
their unconditional ally and very
powerful they have nuclear weapons and
they probably see themselves the
Israelis as that they should be the
dominant power in the region the
regional hedgeim and Iran is a problem
for them because Iran also has similar
ambitions So that's why one of the two
has to go apparently. So that's that's
how it is. And both see each other as as
an existential threat. Iran sees well
the Iranian regime of the Ayatollah they
they they see Israel as a neo- colonial
project and an illegitimate nation and a
nation that doesn't deserve to exist
which obviously Israel doesn't ex agree
with and they see that as as an
existential threat for them and that's
why the two nations are antagonists.
Right? That's that's how it is. So
that's their national interest. That's
their that's their priorities. That is
how they see uh you know their threat
perception
and so on so forth. That that that's how
I would analyze it. Okay. A few more
questions. John says, "How do we
discover our own rare earths?" I think
India has about 10 to 15 or 20% of the
world's rare earth reserves known to
exist. But so we know that it exists.
Okay. But we haven't ever bothered to
develop the mining and extraction
process and and and purification
process. The Chinese have done that. We
have not done it. It will take us at
least a decade to do that. So that's the
thing. We have rare earths at least 10%
if not if not more of the world's rare
earths. That's a that's a sizable
amount. That's definitely enough for our
own requirements that we don't have to
depend on anybody else. We may even end
up being an exporter, but we are not
doing a thing about it.
Rishik says, "When is the next
understanding America?" It's kind of
delayed. I mean, there are two more
episodes that have been recorded. They
need some editing to be done and all
that. And I need to find a slot in which
to release them. So, coming up soon,
reasonably soon. I know it's delayed and
I apologize for that. It'll come soon.
And I I appreciate you're asking this
question. I'm glad that some people are
interested in this. Yeah. Anish says,
"Off topic, no one talks about the bad
mess food in this country. Even top
engineering colleges fail to provide
decent meals to students. This could
have something to do with corruption
perhaps. I don't know. It's terrible. Um
I also have been a student in a hostel
long back. The food was well it was
okay. It was edible usually to some
extent. I I probably did not have that
bad of a mess food. I know people who
have had terrible mess food. So yeah,
it's it's sad that it's the case. I mean
you paying so much money to your to your
engineering college, but they will
provide you with the sort of slop which
I don't understand why.
Dhir Kamat says Chinese Indian rivalry
engineered by the west. Not quite. Not
quite.
It started with the Chinese takeover of
Tibet.
That had nothing to do with the west. It
had everything to do with us acting like
a weak nation. Our leadership behaving
like that. And obviously if you leave a
power vacuum
in a big region, somebody will fill fill
it. Russian to fill it. So Mahatong took
over Tibet and Mr. Neu pro supplied rice
to his soldiers to do that
and then after taking Tibet they took a
chin that they are claiming Arunachas
Pradesh and they are refusing to
demarcate the border. This is entirely
the doing of the Chinese Communist
Party. It has nothing to do with the
west. All right.
Vidi has advice on dealing with
parentification. Common problem. What is
parentification? You mean becoming a new
parent is it?
Um,
I'm not sure what parentification means.
Dealing with parentification.
Does it mean becoming a new parent or
does it mean dealing with your parents?
I'm I'm not quite sure. I'm sorry. Uh,
Vina Jooshi says channel stuck at 950
shadowban. What's the plan? The plan you
go on. Don't worry about what you can't
control.
Why worry about something that's beyond
your control? Be happy. Live your life.
do what you want to do and let it be.
Dr. Patnak says Turkey supported
Pakistan, not India. It's pure religion.
Well, from Turkish perspective, they
have their own agenda. They have their
own perspective. They have their own
religion and so on. Yeah.
Yeah. So, a lot of it has to do with
religion for sure. A lot of it.
Okay. Sabir Chavan says, "Bookshelf tour
also. Did you get a chance to explore?"
Yeah. I haven't done that yet. Yeah. I
haven't seen that yet.
Does it help normal public or only for
big companies? I'll have to see that. I
still haven't done it. I apologize. I I
said I would do it, but I still haven't
found the time to do that. I'm sorry.
Bookshelf tour. I think I have to do it
on a live stream only because Yeah,
maybe I should do a live stream of a
bookshelf tour. Take the camera, take
it, take it, and do a
do a bookshelf tour. I to get it to
focus properly.
Maybe I should do a live stream or maybe
I should put up photographs, pictures of
the books or something.
Okay. Uh Vamshi says, "Look for
skeletons in Kashmir area to find oldest
humans." Possibly. Kashmir is a cooler
place compared to
other parts of India. Kashmir is
reasonably cool. It has snow also at
times. So maybe you could find more
ancient human remains there of our
ancestors which would be interesting
from a genetic and archaeological
perspective. So yeah uh definitely so we
we have some very interesting
archaeological sites in Kashmir. Burom
is an example. Uh there is also uh
uh the discovery that happened a few
years or decades ago of a sky chart in
which there are two suns in the sky and
it turns out to be the oldest ever
depiction of a supernova. So yeah,
there's a lot of interesting history in
Kashmir and I'm sure if you look for it
properly, you may find ancient human
remains which would Yeah, which would
throw a lot of new light on our deep
history. Pravin Allure, thank you very
much, sir. Thank you. Uh Ankita says,
"Apologies for the spelling mistake. My
keyboard is hyper sensitive today. Some
issues with also." No, no issues at all
and no issues. Why don't you apologize?
It's all right. And thank you. Thank you
so much. Uh, Rams says, "What's your
thought on star missile DRDO?" I haven't
heard of the star missile. What is a
star missile? Let me look at it. I'm
curious. What's a star missile DRDO?
Let's see. Star missile DRDO. What is
that? Star missile enters final testing
stage in India's DRDO.
Star missile to simulate supersonic
threats across etc etc. DRDO continues
advances star missile development. What
is this stuff?
uh bolstering supersonic. It's a target
missile. It's a high speed target to
trade air defense unit. Okay. Yeah. Good
job. Good job. It's it's good progress.
So it's so when you're training your air
defense systems, you need targets,
right? So you need target missiles. So
it's a target missile for that. Good.
I'm glad we have it. Supersonic target
missile. Okay. Naman Singh says, "Follow
up from yesterday's question of
indigenous technology ecosystem. Do you
think Indians and government are the
main reasons why we haven't made it?
They want to use foreign products not
have guts like China, Russia. Um I don't
think that's the reason. If you look at
the government of India, well when it
comes to the recent for example, here's
the example operation Synindur, we use
so much indigenous technology which
turned out to be better than something
you would actually import.
We use a lot of our indigenous systems.
Um so I think the government is is
definitely the especially the current
government the Modi government they want
to prioritize indigenization of
everything at bharat so that's not the
case I think the government of India
says that this stuff should be done by
the private sector perhaps I don't know
I'm I'm not sure quite why it's the case
and when it comes to the people of India
sure we the people of India do have this
thing in their mind that foreign
technology is better than Indian
technology so that could be one of the
reasons but I think one of the reasons
is the private sector is is is risk
averse and they don't want to reinvent
the wheel. It's already there in the
west. Why do we need to reinvent do it
all over again? That sort of thing. So I
think it will take some initiative from
the government of India for this to
happen perhaps. Yeah.
Uh Joy Rebel Star says is Bitcoin really
independent?
Um I'm not sure 100% of whether it's
really independent. I really haven't
dipped into this technology. uh I don't
have any Bitcoin investments or
whatever. So I'm not sure what the deal
is but there's always the question mark
all these things I would say. So I'm not
sure. I personally am not sure. Um
says 25 years old doomed careers because
of because of three years gap. What
three years gap?
You're 25 years old. Your career is
already doomed. You're just starting off
at the age of 25. You're starting off in
life. Why is your career doomed? You
have a three-ear gap in something.
It's it doesn't mean your career is
doomed. Don't see it that way. Maybe the
threeear gap of whatever it is may think
may make things difficult for you, but
you don't give up your fight.
People have surmounted much bigger
problems. Don't think of it as as a
doomed career. So without knowing what
the gap is, I don't know really know
what to say, but I would say be
positive. Don't see it as a doomed
career. fight. As long as you are alive,
you're going to fight and you're going
to strive to achieve whatever your
dreams and aspirations are. All right,
sir. All the best.
Naman Singh says, "Even my new page
which was growing at rocket speed was
banned by Instagram. Same shadow ban on
you. That's why dependency is not good
on us apps. Dependency on other apps is
never good. I'm not sure if there's a
shadow ban on me, but whatever." Uh, but
your new page was banned by Instagram.
Well, that's terrible. Unfortunate,
right? So when you have when you are
dependent on foreign platforms you are
at that mercy which is why it would be
great if India develops its own
platform. So I completely agree with you
sir. Uh Vidi is now clarifying parents
wants want kids to fulfill their dreams
and roles. Look Vidi I'll tell you this
we have to respect our parents. Our
parents grow up in a different time and
space essentially in a different era.
Even 20 30 years makes a big difference
and they will see the world in a certain
way. Most people are not are unable to
adapt their their their understanding of
the world as the times change as the
years pass. They most people are stuck
in a different time zone in a different
era and they look at the world from that
perspective. It's not their fault,
right? So if they want kids to do
certain things, maybe it's because they
love them
or maybe it's because in some cases
parents have some dreams of their own
and they expect their kids to fulfill
those dreams or something. Well, that's
that's unfortunate. So my point is this.
Look, you have to cherish and love and
respect your parents. No question about
it. No question about it. But don't be
afraid to disappoint your parents if
need be. Don't disrespect your parents.
Do love your parents. Do cherish your
parents. But al also remember you are
not necessarily responsible for carrying
out their orders for the rest of your
life. Each human being was born to
fulfill a certain purpose in life.
You are not born
with the objective of making somebody
happy. You have to make yourself happy.
Right? So you know if if your
aspirations and objectives are
different from those of your parents you
have to tell them nicely respectfully
and make them understand. If they don't
understand well too bad right? But you
have to follow your dreams your own
dreams and aspirations. Otherwise what
happens is that at a later stage in your
life at some stage in your life your
parents will no longer be with you but
you will be stuck because of your
decision to follow their whatever they
wanted and then you will have this
bitterness for the rest of your life you
should not be should not be there so
don't
do something that is contrary to your
interests and aspirations okay Takur
says the R1A diversity you said is
because of India's last
Though Indians are nearly twice as many
as European submission groups have.
Okay, sir. All right. Okay. Yes, sir.
You must be right. You must be right.
Okay. I am not going to argue with you.
Okay. So, with that, we are at the end
of today's session. It's almost 1 hour
20 minutes and uh yeah, so I'm going to
end it over here. Thank you so much
everybody for all your questions. I hope
that this provided some value to all of
you. Right, you hopefully learn learned
a few things and I will see you tomorrow
in the big uh Ask a Bajit session, the
the regular regularly scheduled weekend
session which could be about 3 hours
long. So I look forward to talking to
you all tomorrow evening 8:00 p.m. Until
then, as always, keep asking questions,
keep learning, keep striving, keep
raising your standards. Never settle for
mediocrity. Always settle for
excellence. Always strive for
excellence. All right. Thank you so
much. I'll see you tomorrow. Bye-bye.